

MAYANK SHARMA

Senior Software Engineer

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic, passionate, fast learner and motivated individual with an 3+ years of Industry Experience, 2+ years of team leading and hands-on experience on testing and developing full stack web applications, seeking Full Stack Software Engineer position in an industry leading company, where I can use my problem-solving skills to the advantage of the company and provide Technical Solutions while having the scope of growing my own skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Barclays Global Service Centre Pvt Ltd

Dec 2022-Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Understanding Business requirement and creating certain matrices and providing automation solutions
- Creating variety of Dashboards using Tableau Desktop
- Web Designing, Development and UI Updates
- Full Stack Web Application Development using .Net and C#
- Database Management and Development
- Microservices handling and development in .Net
- Creating Windows Applications using WPF and C#
- Part of Tech Strategy Team

Tata Consultancy Services Pvt Ltd

Programmer

Oct 2021-Nov 2022

- Working in a customer facing team
- Creating scripts according to requirements sent by the client
- Writing a program in Eclipse IDE using Core Java and Selenium
- Fetching Data from Oracle Database to confirm value of the data
- Managing events that helps in increasing associate's morale, confidence and efficiency in their work.
- Team Leading and Managing time and resources of the team.
- Provided Consulting Services to the client

Tata Consultancy Services Pvt Ltd

Graduate Trainee

Oct 2020-Sept 2021

- Involved in Multiple High-End Projects for US Based Large MNC
- Creating Scripts as according to requirements sent by client
- Manually Testing Software using Industry Standard Tools, like HP ALM

CONTACT

Phone

+91-9311651697

Address

T-12, Naveen Shahdara, Delhi-110032

Email

mayanksharma61099@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/mayank-sharma-ab9784121/

Website

https://main.dxcfbwiclh4mm.amplif yapp.com/

EDUCATION

Master's in Business Administration | June 2024

NMIMS University (GPA: 6.10)

Learnings:

- Business Communications
- Information System for Managers
- Time Management
- Leadership Skills

Masters in Computer Applications | Nov 2022

Amity University (CGPA: 6.61)

Learnings:

- Data Structures.
- Cloud Infrastructure and Services,
- Network Security and Cryptography

RELATED PROJECTS

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE

- A website containing all my with highly responsive UI. User can have all the
 details about my skills, experience and Education, my personal projects, blogs,
 achievements, and how to contact me.
- URL: https://main.dxcfbwiclh4mm.amplifyapp.com/
- Technology Used: React js, Next js, GitHub, AWS

AYURVEDA CLINIC WEBSITE + WEB APPLICATION

- A highly enriched medical website is connected to a backed application architecture which creates a special combination to process the workflow of a clinic efficiently and provides assistance in Backend Data Processing.
- URL: https://www.ayurvedajya.com
- Technology Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap

CUSTOMER RELATION MANAGEMENT

- CRM is developed for End User having various features to maintain a track record and escalation matrix for technical sales of software for Scalability of a fast-paced business environment.
- Technology Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap

BOUTIQUE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

- A high-end application developed with secure and scalable UI, using Java and MySOL to support and maintain boutique storage and warehouse data.
- Technology Used: Java, MySQL

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Successfully organised and coordinated many events in college
- Scored 3rd Position in Paper Mache Competition
- Awarded with On-the-Spot Award twice for good performance in the TCS Team.
- Awarded with On-the-Spot Award for creative initiatives for different teams in TCS
- Received Multiple Recognition in Barclays.
- Successfully Delivered many live projects to different companies.

Bachelors in Computer Applications | Oct 2020

Jagan Institute of Management Studies, GGSIPU (CGPA: 8.37)

Learnings:

- Web Technologies,
- Object-oriented Programming,
- Software Engineering

SKILLS

Java

C#

JavaScript

Asp.Net

Python

React JS

GitHub

CSS

HTML

Python

Technical Review

System Architecture

Web Technologies

REFERENCES

Manish Sharma

CEO, Whiz Adverts

Contact Number: +91-9811051697

Girish Bhardwaj

Doctor, Ayurvedajya

Contact Number: +91-9958414144

Shubham Saurabh

Team Lead, TCS

Contact Number: +1 (317) 658-3497